<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2020-10-24T06:22:49+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">20,000 Years of Dance Music</title><subtitle>Made with &lt;b style=&quot;color: #f45;&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;3&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/niklasbuschmann&quot;&gt;@niklasbuschmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;</subtitle><author><name>hullboy73</name></author><entry><title type="html">We are the Dollars and Cents</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/we-are-the-dollars-and-cents/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We are the Dollars and Cents" /><published>2020-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/we-are-the-dollars-and-cents</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/we-are-the-dollars-and-cents/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/farm-2852024_640.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crypto Mining Apparatus&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deadlines can be helpful things. I stayed up deep into the morning to get an article penned for a writing competition of sorts on a website called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publish0x.com/&quot;&gt;Publish0x&lt;/a&gt;. If you fancy joining and giving it a go please click this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publish0x.com?a=YQdJ6G1JdO&quot;&gt;affiliate link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I get here? For years I’ve abstained from using advertising on the internet - not littering my websites with Google ads and generally using an Adblocker for my internet travels. Suddenly there’s quite a leap. Overnight I write &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publish0x.com/20-minutes-of-peace-and-quiet/dexg-the-cryptocurrency-seeking-to-curb-volatility-xpjgogw&quot;&gt;an article which is basically an advert for some zonkers crypto company in Singapore&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t feel very good about this. This is pretty low in the barrel behaviour to be effectively contributing fake news (well… fake opinion) to the internet. The desperation on my part is perhaps less about money and more about wanting to put something out there maybe but…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at it from a more positive angle I think there’s something to be credited about the more typical working practice of Publish0x. The essential concept is that you earn money (Ethereum tokens) for both reading and writing articles on the website. The occupying authorities in internet land (Google, Facebook, Amazon, Apple, Microsoft) continue to return approximately zilch credit or rewards for their users’ ongoing attention. OK, that’s not exactly true. They provide many free services with marvellous facilities for connection over some kind of cabled/mobile infrastructure, but the pressure is mounting on these corporations to give something in credit or even stake back to their users for the powerful leverage provided them by streamed channels of user data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The services provided by these big tech corporations are underpinned, founded and served on open source technologies. In such ways the fundamentals of the internet remain free and open source. The more people realise the extent and misuse of their personal data and the technological infrastructure of their commons the more vocal the demand for a different kind of internet. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publish0x.com/&quot;&gt;Publish0x&lt;/a&gt; is not really that, much as &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/&quot;&gt;Brave Browser&lt;/a&gt; (ads you are rewarded for clicking on) is not, but they are moves in a different direction. They recognise and make some means of addressing the inequitable distribution of internet wealth. They credit you with something (small) for your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty much a newbie to the crypto scene but there’s a sense of excitement in the areas of crypto-currency investment and blockchain technologies right now. The two fields are closely interlinked so we see a curious mix of goldrush capitalism (DeFi) and communitarian promise in decentralised, blockchain networks. Projects such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blockstack.org/&quot;&gt;Blockstack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://telegram.org/&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://threefold.io/&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;/a&gt; are all worth reading about. They hark back to some long-held, more altruistic hopes for the internet - see &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedomboxfoundation.org/&quot;&gt;The Internet Needs Freedom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I seem to have run to the end of my spirited little editorial here. A few other interesting reads of note regarding these technological developments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lex.substack.com/&quot;&gt;The Fintech Blueprint&lt;/a&gt; - change in the financial sector&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.matthewball.vc/all/audiotech&quot;&gt;Audio’s Opportunity and Who Will Capture It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://kernel.community/&quot;&gt;Kernel Community&lt;/a&gt; - philosophical ideas on coding for long-term change&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>hullboy73</name></author><summary type="html">Deadlines can be helpful things. I stayed up deep into the morning to get an article penned for a writing competition of sorts on a website called Publish0x. If you fancy joining and giving it a go please click this affiliate link. How did I get here? For years I’ve abstained from using advertising on the internet - not littering my websites with Google ads and generally using an Adblocker for my internet travels. Suddenly there’s quite a leap. Overnight I write an article which is basically an advert for some zonkers crypto company in Singapore. I don’t feel very good about this. This is pretty low in the barrel behaviour to be effectively contributing fake news (well… fake opinion) to the internet. The desperation on my part is perhaps less about money and more about wanting to put something out there maybe but… Looking at it from a more positive angle I think there’s something to be credited about the more typical working practice of Publish0x. The essential concept is that you earn money (Ethereum tokens) for both reading and writing articles on the website. The occupying authorities in internet land (Google, Facebook, Amazon, Apple, Microsoft) continue to return approximately zilch credit or rewards for their users’ ongoing attention. OK, that’s not exactly true. They provide many free services with marvellous facilities for connection over some kind of cabled/mobile infrastructure, but the pressure is mounting on these corporations to give something in credit or even stake back to their users for the powerful leverage provided them by streamed channels of user data. The services provided by these big tech corporations are underpinned, founded and served on open source technologies. In such ways the fundamentals of the internet remain free and open source. The more people realise the extent and misuse of their personal data and the technological infrastructure of their commons the more vocal the demand for a different kind of internet. Publish0x is not really that, much as Brave Browser (ads you are rewarded for clicking on) is not, but they are moves in a different direction. They recognise and make some means of addressing the inequitable distribution of internet wealth. They credit you with something (small) for your attention. I’m pretty much a newbie to the crypto scene but there’s a sense of excitement in the areas of crypto-currency investment and blockchain technologies right now. The two fields are closely interlinked so we see a curious mix of goldrush capitalism (DeFi) and communitarian promise in decentralised, blockchain networks. Projects such as IPFS, Blockstack, Telegram and ThreeFold are all worth reading about. They hark back to some long-held, more altruistic hopes for the internet - see The Internet Needs Freedom. I seem to have run to the end of my spirited little editorial here. A few other interesting reads of note regarding these technological developments: The Fintech Blueprint - change in the financial sector Audio’s Opportunity and Who Will Capture It Kernel Community - philosophical ideas on coding for long-term change</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Numerai dataset crashes my Jupyter Notebook and Linux PC</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/numerai-dataset-crashes-my-jupyter-notebook-and-linux-pc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Numerai dataset crashes my Jupyter Notebook and Linux PC" /><published>2020-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/numerai-dataset-crashes-my-jupyter-notebook-and-linux-pc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/numerai-dataset-crashes-my-jupyter-notebook-and-linux-pc/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/numerai_20200929.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Numerai Submission Reminder Message&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how did I come across &lt;a href=&quot;https://numer.ai/tournament&quot;&gt;Numerai&lt;/a&gt;, the tournament for would-be quants to predict stock market movement?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started off with cryptocurrency. Numeraire sits at the very bottom of cryptocurrency stocks running on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/price&quot;&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt; exchange (or index or what have you) in terms of market cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah… Numerai. It’s pretty lousy. It’s a hedge fund itself actually (although competitors in the tournament have zero stake in the hedge fund… they just do the grunt work to build it). And since random forests and XGBoost and AutoML have pretty much got machine learning down to a T… er… it’s all going nowhere really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What most annoys me about Numerai is the size of the dataset. Weekly data must be downloaded and the size of this file unzipped is 3.5GB. That’s do-able but running pandas read_csv() on it has thrown a wobbly to break my machine time and time again. Because I don’t have enough RAM or grunt power. My machine shouldn’t really crash (that’s a quite serious problem I am having with Linux right now, I guess) but Jupyter Notebook is going to crash. I maybe have 12GB RAM in this machine (which is not all that tiny really) but it’s not going to cut it for analysing this Numerai dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way around it is to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Colab&lt;/a&gt; instead of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter.org/&quot;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; notebooks. It worked for me. Oh no… ‘Your session crashed after using all available RAM’. At least Google Colab crashes my process but not my whole machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve managed but been late with my submissions for the first two weeks of my entry into the Numerai tournament. It’s a start though. But now I need to learn how to use Google Colab. Quite enjoying it though, mostly fussing about at this stage putting datasets and models into different folders (which is not high-end machine learning). And thinking about it with a bit of perspective too. Thinking: Individual competitors competing on a fairly inane question (predicting the movement of market stocks) by seeing who can throw the fastest, biggest computer force at some pretty large datasets… what’s to like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point for readers here is just that if your PC has similar modest specs and your exploratory/analytical notebook (or even computer) is crashing when reading the Numerai dataset it’s due to a lack of computer power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/gb/title/81254224&quot;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;/a&gt; actually, which was quite good (silly in places). I was pleased to see a major film exploring the alarming impact of profit-motivated algorithms on social networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discogs.com/Various-Lazy-Dog/master/232788&quot;&gt;Lazy Dog&lt;/a&gt;, a 2-CD set of deep house from 2000. Lazy Dog was a club night held in a small basement club in Notting Hill in the late nineties. Deep house, according to Wikipedia, ‘rarely reaches a climax, but lingers on as a comfortable, hypnotic and relaxing pulse, perfect for the small, dimly lit nightclub.’ I’ve worn my ears out with it a bit now but it’s a very nice couple of mixes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>hullboy73</name></author><summary type="html">So how did I come across Numerai, the tournament for would-be quants to predict stock market movement? It started off with cryptocurrency. Numeraire sits at the very bottom of cryptocurrency stocks running on the Coinbase exchange (or index or what have you) in terms of market cap. So yeah… Numerai. It’s pretty lousy. It’s a hedge fund itself actually (although competitors in the tournament have zero stake in the hedge fund… they just do the grunt work to build it). And since random forests and XGBoost and AutoML have pretty much got machine learning down to a T… er… it’s all going nowhere really. What most annoys me about Numerai is the size of the dataset. Weekly data must be downloaded and the size of this file unzipped is 3.5GB. That’s do-able but running pandas read_csv() on it has thrown a wobbly to break my machine time and time again. Because I don’t have enough RAM or grunt power. My machine shouldn’t really crash (that’s a quite serious problem I am having with Linux right now, I guess) but Jupyter Notebook is going to crash. I maybe have 12GB RAM in this machine (which is not all that tiny really) but it’s not going to cut it for analysing this Numerai dataset. The way around it is to use Google Colab instead of Jupyter notebooks. It worked for me. Oh no… ‘Your session crashed after using all available RAM’. At least Google Colab crashes my process but not my whole machine. I’ve managed but been late with my submissions for the first two weeks of my entry into the Numerai tournament. It’s a start though. But now I need to learn how to use Google Colab. Quite enjoying it though, mostly fussing about at this stage putting datasets and models into different folders (which is not high-end machine learning). And thinking about it with a bit of perspective too. Thinking: Individual competitors competing on a fairly inane question (predicting the movement of market stocks) by seeing who can throw the fastest, biggest computer force at some pretty large datasets… what’s to like? My point for readers here is just that if your PC has similar modest specs and your exploratory/analytical notebook (or even computer) is crashing when reading the Numerai dataset it’s due to a lack of computer power. I watched The Social Dilemma actually, which was quite good (silly in places). I was pleased to see a major film exploring the alarming impact of profit-motivated algorithms on social networking. Listening to Lazy Dog, a 2-CD set of deep house from 2000. Lazy Dog was a club night held in a small basement club in Notting Hill in the late nineties. Deep house, according to Wikipedia, ‘rarely reaches a climax, but lingers on as a comfortable, hypnotic and relaxing pulse, perfect for the small, dimly lit nightclub.’ I’ve worn my ears out with it a bit now but it’s a very nice couple of mixes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Create a GitHub Pages blog on Ubuntu Linux with local build</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/create-github-pages-blog-on-ubuntu-linux-with-local-build/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Create a GitHub Pages blog on Ubuntu Linux with local build" /><published>2020-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/create-github-pages-blog-on-ubuntu-linux-with-local-build</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/create-github-pages-blog-on-ubuntu-linux-with-local-build/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/4943215/74586452-bcb15780-4fe7-11ea-94a8-7a9b52bf04b3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Laptop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big, big shout out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://aryamurali.com/&quot;&gt;Arya Murali&lt;/a&gt; and her comprehensive guide on Medium to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/20percentwork/creating-your-blog-for-free-using-jekyll-github-pages-dba37272730a&quot;&gt;Creating your blog for free using Jekyll + Github pages&lt;/a&gt;. That’s the definitive and really spot on guide to how to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could attempt to rewrite the whole of that article in my own words and I’ve had a go but it’s so well written and clear that I’ll just direct you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/20percentwork/creating-your-blog-for-free-using-jekyll-github-pages-dba37272730a&quot;&gt;that tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;The GitHub Pages welcome page&lt;/a&gt; provides an easier method to setting up a blog on GitHub Pages but it won’t enable you to build your website locally on your machine and push the changes from there. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/20percentwork/creating-your-blog-for-free-using-jekyll-github-pages-dba37272730a&quot;&gt;This tutorial&lt;/a&gt; is a thorough guide to how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m running on a Ubuntu 18.04 Linux platform so in terms of installing packages and dependencies start with this at the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;apt-get &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;ruby  
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;gem &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;jekyll bundler&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything else &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/20percentwork/creating-your-blog-for-free-using-jekyll-github-pages-dba37272730a&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; should be straight-forward enough. It is a kind of complicated process. One of the confusing things is you build offline &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; creating a repository on GitHub Pages. Another issue that’s often mentioned in similar guides (I’ve read quite a lot) is checking out to the gh-pages branch. I don’t understand any of that but it’s all set out in &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/20percentwork/creating-your-blog-for-free-using-jekyll-github-pages-dba37272730a&quot;&gt;the guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- From the browser or command line go to [http://127.0.0.1:4000](http://127.0.0.1:4000) and check out your new blog.  

These are the essential instructions that are frustratingly absent from a lot of guides but were made explicit in [the marvellous tutorial/guide mentioned above](https://medium.com/20percentwork/creating-your-blog-for-free-using-jekyll-github-pages-dba37272730a). I'm just passing on some useful information. We're kind of only halfway there because the blog is not yet set up on GitHub Pages. Again this is confusing because the trick is to set up create the repository offline (as we just did with the jekyll serve command) before creating the repository on GitHub Pages. [Arya's tutorial](https://medium.com/20percentwork/creating-your-blog-for-free-using-jekyll-github-pages-dba37272730a) takes you carefully step-by-step through that process.  

So on GitHub Pages you create a new repository. This is achieved via the plus button at the top right of the screen. You enter your_blog_name exactly as you set it up with jekyll earlier in the Repository name box. Don't initialize the repository with a README. Just hit the Create repository green button and stop right there. We're going to 'push an existing repository from the command line'. --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m not exactly new to blogging or using GitHub but I do get a bit tied up in knots when trying to work my way through this stuff. Jekyll has a decent and not too long &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/step-by-step/01-setup/&quot;&gt;Step by Step Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; which I’ll have to read again. I jump into these things and only really understand what’s happening after I’ve haphazardly come across and typed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/20percentwork/creating-your-blog-for-free-using-jekyll-github-pages-dba37272730a&quot;&gt;the correct instructions&lt;/a&gt; I needed to get it to work. That’s pretty much my amateur way in. The GitHub Pages docs were maddening. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/step-by-step/02-liquid/&quot;&gt;Liquid templating&lt;/a&gt; looks tricky. It’s all coded in Ruby this static website stuff, Jekyll and so forth. I remember that fantastic comic guide to Ruby - Why’s comic guide or something? What was that called? &lt;a href=&quot;https://poignant.guide/&quot;&gt;Why’s (Poignant) Guide to Ruby&lt;/a&gt;. There are static site generators for Python, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.getpelican.com/&quot;&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; and now I understand a bit more how it works I could have a look at that maybe or perhaps just stick with Ruby and Jekyll and a just about working website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/35077507/how-to-right-align-and-justify-align-in-markdown&quot;&gt;how do I justify paragraphs?&lt;/a&gt; This is gonna’ be harder than I thought…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>hullboy73</name></author><summary type="html">Big, big shout out to Arya Murali and her comprehensive guide on Medium to Creating your blog for free using Jekyll + Github pages. That’s the definitive and really spot on guide to how to do this. I could attempt to rewrite the whole of that article in my own words and I’ve had a go but it’s so well written and clear that I’ll just direct you to that tutorial. The GitHub Pages welcome page provides an easier method to setting up a blog on GitHub Pages but it won’t enable you to build your website locally on your machine and push the changes from there. This tutorial is a thorough guide to how to do that. I’m running on a Ubuntu 18.04 Linux platform so in terms of installing packages and dependencies start with this at the command line. $ sudo apt-get install ruby $ gem install jekyll bundler Everything else here should be straight-forward enough. It is a kind of complicated process. One of the confusing things is you build offline before creating a repository on GitHub Pages. Another issue that’s often mentioned in similar guides (I’ve read quite a lot) is checking out to the gh-pages branch. I don’t understand any of that but it’s all set out in the guide. So I’m not exactly new to blogging or using GitHub but I do get a bit tied up in knots when trying to work my way through this stuff. Jekyll has a decent and not too long Step by Step Tutorial which I’ll have to read again. I jump into these things and only really understand what’s happening after I’ve haphazardly come across and typed in the correct instructions I needed to get it to work. That’s pretty much my amateur way in. The GitHub Pages docs were maddening. Liquid templating looks tricky. It’s all coded in Ruby this static website stuff, Jekyll and so forth. I remember that fantastic comic guide to Ruby - Why’s comic guide or something? What was that called? Why’s (Poignant) Guide to Ruby. There are static site generators for Python, such as Pelican and now I understand a bit more how it works I could have a look at that maybe or perhaps just stick with Ruby and Jekyll and a just about working website. OK, how do I justify paragraphs? This is gonna’ be harder than I thought…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to 20,000 Years of Dance Music</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-20,000-years-of-dance-music/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to 20,000 Years of Dance Music" /><published>2020-09-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-20,000-years-of-dance-music</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-20,000-years-of-dance-music/">&lt;p&gt;Yay, up and running!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is number one in “the only chart that counts”…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/mood.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>hullboy73</name></author><summary type="html">Yay, up and running! This is number one in “the only chart that counts”…</summary></entry></feed>